CHAPTER 007
Wha—
Wh-Why are you here?
ど どうしてお前がここに...
The one who notified me of "her" will
was Teori-san over there.
意志[いし]:will/volition/intention, わたし:I/me|private affairs, わたし:ferry (crossing)/ferry(boat)|delivery, 伝達[でんたつ]:transmission (e.g. news, chemical signals, electricity)/communication/delivery, あちら:that way (direction distant from both speaker and listener)/over there|that one (something physically distant from both speaker and listener, or something not visible but known by both speaker and listener), いらっしゃる:to come/to go|is (doing), 折[おり]:opportunity|fold|small food box (wooden or cardboard)
"あのかた"の意志をわたしに伝達してくれたのが
あちらにいらっしゃる手折さんなのです
N-Notify?
伝達[でんたつ]:transmission (e.g. news, chemical signals, electricity)/communication/delivery
で... 伝達?
Don't give me that look, Araragi-kun.
顔[かお, がん]:face|look|honor|, 顔[かんばせ]:countenance/visage|face
そんな顔をするなって 阿良々木くん
I'll give you a full round of explanations.
ちゃんと:diligently/seriously|perfectly, 一通り[ひととおり]:(in) general|ordinary|briefly|, 説明[せつめい]:explanation/exposition, あげる:to raise/to elevate|to do up (one's hair)
ちゃんと一通り 説明してあげるからさ
You're, I mean...
お前は だって
a specialist who specializes in the extermination
of immortal apparitions, right?
不死身[ふじみ]:invulnerability/immortality/insensibility to pain, 怪異[かいい]:strangeness/mystery|ghost, 退治[たいじ]:extermination (e.g. of pests, demons, bandits)|making someone renounce worldly desires in order to concentrate on Buddha's teachings|curing illness, 専門[せんもん]:speciality/specialty/subject of study, 専門家[せんもんか]:specialist/expert/professional
不死身の怪異の退治を専門とする専門家 なんだろう?
You don't have to worry
about that for now.
心配[しんぱい]:worry/concern|care
今は心配しなくてもいいよ
What?
From you, your vampiric nature...
吸血鬼[きゅうけつき]:vampire/bloodsucker, 性[さが, なりくせ]:one's nature/one's destiny|custom, 性[せい]:nature (of a person)|sex|gender|
きみからは吸血鬼性が...
...has been subtracted.
引き算[ひきざん]:subtraction
引き算されている
Oh, I see.
ああ... そうか
So that's what Hachikuji meant
about what she said earlier.
さっき:some time ago/just now, さっき:thirst for blood/bloodlust/determination to kill, 寺[てら]:temple (Buddhist), 寺[じ]:counter for temples, 意味[いみ]:meaning/significance
さっき八九寺が言っていたのは そういう意味だったのか
It wasn't just multiplication and division,
but there's subtraction involved as well.
掛ける[かける]:to hang (e.g. picture)|to sit|to take (time, money)||, 割る[わる]:to divide|to cut|to break||, 引き算[ひきざん]:subtraction
"掛けて割る" だけじゃあなくて "引き算" もされるという
The subtracted number
was my vampiric nature.
引く[ひく]:to pull|to draw (attention, etc.)|to draw back||, 数字[すうじ]:numeral/figure/digit, 吸血鬼[きゅうけつき]:vampire/bloodsucker, 性[さが, なりくせ]:one's nature/one's destiny|custom, 性[せい]:nature (of a person)|sex|gender|
引く数字は 吸血鬼性だったのか
Is Yotsugi doing well? I hope she didn't
worry about the fact that she killed me.
余接[よせつ]:cotangent, 元気[げんき]:lively/full of spirit|healthy, 気に病む[きにやむ]:to worry/to fret (over something)/to be worried
余接は元気にしているかな?
私を殺したことを 気に病んでなければいいんだけれど
After all, she wasn't told
of the circumstances that we were in.
なにせ:at any rate/anyhow, 事情[じじょう]:circumstances/consideration/conditions, 知らす[しらす]:to inform|to know|to reign
なにせあの子は事情を知らされていなかったからねえ
What were the circumstances?
事情[じじょう]:circumstances/consideration/conditions
事情って... なんだ?
To put it plainly...
端的[たんてき]:frank/direct/plain
端的に言うなら...
Being killed by Yotsugi in that manner
was the true role that had been given to me.
余接[よせつ]:cotangent, 課す[かす]:to levy/to charge/to assess, 役割[やくわり]:part/assigning (allotment of) parts/role
ああやって余接に殺されることこそが
私に課されていた本当の役割だったということだ
To fall to hell ahead of time, and have
all preparations to resurrect you be completed.
先[さき]:previous|point (e.g. pencil)|head (of a line)||, 先[せん]:former/previous|first move (in go, shogi, etc.), 地獄[じごく]:hell, 落ちる[おちる]:to fall down|to be omitted|to decrease||, 生き返る[いきかえる]:to revive/to come to oneself/to be restored to life, 準備[じゅんび]:preparation/setup/arrangements, 整える[ととのえる]:to put in order|to get ready|to raise money
先に地獄に落ちておいて
きみを生き返らせる準備を整えておくことが
That was my job as a professional specialist.
専門家[せんもんか]:specialist/expert/professional, 仕事[しごと]:work/job|work
プロの専門家としての 私の仕事だった
MAYOI HELL - PART TWO
CHAPTER 008
Huh?
...は?
FIVE MINUTES LATER
You mean you feigned death?
振り[ふり]:swing|appearance|pretence (pretense)||, 振り[ぶり]:style/manner|after (period of time) again (e.g. meeting again after a year)
し 死んだ振りってこと?
The individual known as me had already
passed away at a point in the distant past.
個人[こじん]:individual/private person/personal, かなり:considerably/fairly/quite, 昔[むかし]:olden days/former, 段階[だんかい]:grade/level/stage, 段階[きざはし, きだはし]:stairs|stairs at the front of a noh stage, 既に[すでに, すんでに]:already/too late
私という個人は かなり昔の段階で既に死んでいたんだ
Back then, my self that Yotsugi killed
was a puppet that I controlled.
余接[よせつ]:cotangent, 操る[あやつる]:to manipulate|to have a good command of (a language)|to operate a puppet||, 人形[にんぎょう]:doll/puppet/figure
あのとき 余接が殺した私は 私の操る人形だよ
You said that Ononoki-chan
didn't know about that?
斧[おの]:axe/hatchet, 乃[の]:possessive particle, 木[き]:tree/shrub|wood, 木[もく]:Thursday|wood (first of the five elements)
斧乃木ちゃんは... それを知らなかったって
言ってたよな?
Yup, that's right. Not just Yotsugi,
but Yoduru didn't know, either.
余接[よせつ]:cotangent, 余弦[よげん]:cosine
うん そうだ
余接だけじゃない 余弦も知らなかった
The ones who knew about this technique were
手法[しゅほう]:technique/method
私のこの手法を知っていたのは
Gaen-senpai, and Meme Oshino.
Nobody else.
先輩[せんぱい]:senior (at work or school)/superior/elder, 野[の, や]:plain|hidden (structural) member|wild|
臥煙先輩と そして 忍野メメだけだ
If so, then what in the world was that farce?
いったい:...the heck (e.g. "what the heck?")/...in the world (e.g. "why in the world?")|one object, いったい:region/zone/whole place, 茶番[ちゃばん]:farce|person who serves tea|short and humorous improvised sketch (originating from Edo-era kabuki)
だったら... いったいなんだったんだ?
あの茶番は
A farce? That was the best act in my book.
茶番[ちゃばん]:farce|person who serves tea|short and humorous improvised sketch (originating from Edo-era kabuki), 十八番[おはこ, じゅうはちばん]:one's favourite party trick (favorite)|No. 18|repertoire of 18 kabuki plays
茶番か 私としては十八番なんだが
I mean, dying and resurrecting.
生き返る[いきかえる]:to revive/to come to oneself/to be restored to life
死んだり生き返ったりはね
You could say it's my specialty
even more than it is for vampires.
吸血鬼[きゅうけつき]:vampire/bloodsucker, 以上[いじょう]:not less than|beyond ... (e.g. one's means)|above-mentioned||, 得意技[とくいわざ]:signature move (assoc. with a martial artist, wrestler, etc.)/finishing move, とも言う[ともいう]:also called
吸血鬼以上に 得意技だとも言える
Though, strictly speaking,
I'm not really resurrecting back to life.
厳密[げんみつ]:strict/close, 生き返る[いきかえる]:to revive/to come to oneself/to be restored to life, てはい:arrangement/preparations|search (by police), てはい:tiles in a player's hand
まあ 厳密には生き返ってはいないんだけれどね
I am merely possessing a doll,
人形[にんぎょう]:doll/puppet/figure, 憑依[ひょうい]:dependence/depending on|possession (by a spirit, etc.), 媒体[ばいたい]:media/medium, 経る[へる]:to pass|to pass through|to experience
人形に憑依(ひょうい)して 媒体を経て
and through that medium,
I am regressing into the material world.
現世[げんせい, げんせ]:present world/present age|recent epoch (i.e. the Holocene epoch), 回帰[かいき]:return (to)/revolution|regression
現世に回帰しているだけだから
From when?
いつから?
I became a puppeteer
人形[にんぎょう]:doll/puppet/figure, 使い[つかい]:errand|messenger|familiar spirit|
人形使いになるのは
after I created the doll known as Yotsugi,
and parted ways with them.
余接[よせつ]:cotangent, 人形[にんぎょう]:doll/puppet/figure, 作る[つくる]:to make|to prepare (food)|to raise||, 決別[けつべつ]:separation/farewell/parting, 後[あと]:behind|after|after one's death||, 後[のち]:later|future|after one's death|
余接という人形を作り 彼らと決別した後のことだ
Whoa.
おっと:husband, おっと:uh-oh/oops/sorry
おっと
WHITE FRAME
It seems I am being hurried.
急かす[せかす]:to hurry/to urge on
急かされているようだな
Allow me to explain plainly.
端的[たんてき]:frank/direct/plain, 説明[せつめい]:explanation/exposition
端的に説明しよう
I quit college, and entered this field.
やめる:to stop (an activity)/to cease|to cancel, やめる:to resign/to retire/to quit, 道[みち]:road|distance|the way (of proper conduct, etc.)||, 道[どう]:road|way|Buddhist teachings||
大学をやめて この道に入った私だが
But as Gaen-senpai was glaring at me,
I couldn't really get things to go my way.
なにせ:at any rate/anyhow, 先輩[せんぱい]:senior (at work or school)/superior/elder, 睨む[にらむ]:to glare at|to stare intensely at|to estimate||, 身[み]:body|oneself|one's place|, 身[むくろ]:(dead) body/corpse, なかなか:very/considerably|by no means (with negative verb)
なにせ臥煙先輩に睨(にら)まれている身だからね
なかなか思うようにはいかない
So, the hasty decision I had come up with
was to call the forbidden technique.
短絡[たんらく]:electric short-circuit|drawing a hasty inference between two events/jumping to a quick conclusion, 的[てき]:-like/typical, 的[まと]:mark/target, 発想[はっそう]:idea/conception|expression, いわゆる:what is called/as it is called/the so-called, 禁断[きんだん]:prohibition/interdiction|forbidden, 手法[しゅほう]:technique/method
そこで私が短絡的に発想したのは
いわゆる禁断の手法だった
As a specialist, it's too powerful of a spell
to use, more than being a forbidden move.
専門家[せんもんか]:specialist/expert/professional, 禁じ手[きんじて]:forbidden move (sumo, shogi, go, etc.)/prohibited move/foul, 禁[きん]:ban (e.g. on smoking)/prohibition, 呪[じゅ]:spell/curse|dharani, 呪[かしり]:spell/curse, 近い[ちかい]:near|close (in time)|close (relationship)||
専門家としては禁じ手
というより禁呪(きんじゅ)に近い
I had tried to create a doll apparition
named Tadatsuru Teori.
折[おり]:opportunity|fold|small food box (wooden or cardboard), 正弦[せいげん]:sine, 人形[にんぎょう]:doll/puppet/figure, 怪異[かいい]:strangeness/mystery|ghost, 作る[つくる]:to make|to prepare (food)|to raise||
私は 手折正弦という人形怪異を作ろうとした
Did that succeed?
成功[せいこう]:success/hit
成功したのか それが
I failed, and what you see here is the result.
失敗[しっぱい]:failure/mistake/blunder, 結果[けっか]:result/consequence|coming to fruition, 有様[ありさま, ありよう]:state/condition/circumstances
失敗した その結果がこの有様だ
I became something
like half-man and half-monster,
この世[このよ]:this world/the present life (in contrast to the land of the dead), あの世[あのよ]:the other world/world of the dead/netherworld, 狭間[はざま]:interval|valley|loophole (in a wall), 漂う[ただよう]:to drift|to waft (e.g. a scent)|to be in the air (e.g. a feeling or mood)||
私はこの世とあの世の狭間(はざま)を漂(ただよ)う
wandering the boundaries
of the material world and the afterlife.
存在[そんざい]:existence/being
半人半妖のような存在となった
Well, I say it was a failure,
but I can continue to live through my dolls.
失敗[しっぱい]:failure/mistake/blunder, とは言え[とはいえ]:though/although/be that as it may, 人形[にんぎょう]:doll/puppet/figure, 通ずる[つうずる]:to be open (to traffic)|to flow (liquid, current)|to be understood||, 生きる[いきる]:to live|to make a living|to be in effect||
ま 失敗とは言え
人形を通じては生きていられるわけだし
And since then, I succeeded
in the mass-production of the dolls.
その後[そのあと, そのご]:after that/afterwards/thereafter, 人形[にんぎょう]:doll/puppet/figure, 量産[りょうさん]:mass production, 化[か]:action of making something/-ification, 成功[せいこう]:success/hit
その後 人形の量産化には成功したから
So, if you say I'm immortal, I'm immortal.
不老不死[ふろうふし]:perpetual youth and longevity/immortality
不老不死と言えば不老不死
If you say I'm an apparition,
I'm an apparition.
怪異[かいい]:strangeness/mystery|ghost
怪異と言えば怪異だ
At most, I make good use of my special
constitution to strive in my own business.
精々[せいぜい]:at the most/at best/to the utmost, 特異[とくい]:unique/singular, 体質[たいしつ]:constitution (physical)/genetic make-up|structure (e.g. of an organization), 活かす[いかす]:to make (the best) use of|to let live|to revive, 商売[しょうばい]:trade/business/commerce, 励む[はげむ]:to strive/to endeavour/to endeavor, ことにする:to make a distinction/to differ/to be different, ことにする:to decide to|to pretend that
精々その特異体質を活かして
商売に励むことにした
BECAUSE HE HAD SUCH A SPECIAL CONSTITUTION
HE WAS ABLE TO COME THIS FAR OUTSIDE
OF GAEN-SAN'S NETWORK...
Then, why did you pretend to die?
振り[ふり]:swing|appearance|pretence (pretense)||, 振り[ぶり]:style/manner|after (period of time) again (e.g. meeting again after a year), なんか:things like .../or something like that ... (often derogatory), なんか:something
じゃあ どうして 死んだ振りなんか
It was last month.
先月[せんげつ]:last month
先月のことだった
One request came flying for me
as a specialist.
専門家[せんもんか]:specialist/expert/professional, 依頼[いらい]:request/commission|dependence, 舞い込む[まいこむ]:to come fluttering in (e.g. leaves, snow, flowers, etc.)/to come dancing in|to drop in unexpectedly
専門家としての私に ひとつ依頼が舞い込んだ
It was a request to resolve the anomalies
that were happening in your town.
住む[すむ]:to live (of humans)/to reside/to inhabit, 町[まち, ちょう]:town|street|109.09 m||, 起こる[おこる]:to occur/to happen, 異変[いへん]:unusual phenomenon/unusual event/abnormal event, 解決[かいけつ]:settlement/solution/resolution, 欲しい[ほしい]:wanted/wished for|I want (you) to, 依頼[いらい]:request/commission|dependence
きみの住んでいる町で起こっている異変を解決して欲しいという依頼だった
The contents of that request
had targeted you and ex-Kiss-shot.
依頼[いらい]:request/commission|dependence, 内容[ないよう]:subject/contents/matter, 旧[きゅう]:ex-/former/old, 旧[ふる]:used item/secondhand item|old, 的[てき]:-like/typical, 的[まと]:mark/target
その依頼の内容は
きみや旧キスショットを的にしたものだった
You guys were certified as harmless
within Gaen-senpai's network,
先輩[せんぱい]:senior (at work or school)/superior/elder, ネットワーク:network, 内[うち]:inside|while|among||, 内[ない]:inside/within, 無害[むがい]:harmless, 認定[にんてい]:authorization/authorisation/acknowledgment, 達[たち]:pluralizing suffix (esp. for people & animals; formerly honorific), 達[だち, ダチ]:friend, ではある:to be (in contrast to something that is not the case)
臥煙先輩のネットワーク内では無害認定されているきみ達ではあったが
but an apparition guarded by the network
was something I targeted as my top priority.
むしろ:rather/better/instead, むしろ:woven mat (esp. one made of straw)|seat, ネットワーク:network, 保護[ほご, ほうご]:care/protection/shelter, 怪異[かいい]:strangeness/mystery|ghost, 最優先[さいゆうせん]:maximum preference/maximum priority/priority handling, 狙う[ねらう]:to aim at
むしろネットワークで保護されている怪異など
私にとっては最優先で狙うべき
Request or not, you were a target
that I should be on the move for.
依頼[いらい]:request/commission|dependence, 動く[うごく]:to move|to operate|to be touched||, 対象[たいしょう]:target/object (of worship, study, etc.)/subject (of taxation, etc.)
依頼がなくとも動くべき対象だった
This guy took my two little sisters
and one underclassman as hostages.
二人[ふたり, ににん]:two persons/two people/pair, 妹[いもうと]:younger sister, 妹[いも]:darling (only of a woman)|one's sister|friend, 後輩[こうはい]:junior (at work, school, etc.)/younger people/younger student, 一人[ひとり, いちにん]:one person|alone/unmarried, 人質[ひとじち]:hostage, 取る[とる]:to take|to steal|to eat||, なんて:how ..!/what ..!|what (questioning), なんて:such as/(things) like|exclamation
こいつは 二人の妹と後輩を一人
人質に取るなんていう
He pulled off such a vicious, cruel act.
悪辣[あくらつ]:crafty/vicious/unscrupulous, 非道[ひどう]:unjust/inhuman, 真似[まね, マネ]:imitating/copying|behavior, のける:to put something out of the way/to move (something, someone) aside|to remove
悪辣非道(あくらつひどう)な真似をしてのけたのだ
BLACK FRAME
If something had
not been done in advance,
事前[じぜん]:prior/beforehand/in advance, 打つ[うつ]:to hit|to strike (noon, etc.)|to beat (rhythmically, e.g. pulse, waves, etc.)||, 打つ[ぶつ]:to hit (a person)/to strike/to beat
もしも事前に手が打たれていなければ
I wonder if I would have been
unscathed by it all.
果たして[はたして]:as was expected/just as one thought|really? (in questions), 無事[ぶじ]:safety/peace/quietness, 済む[すむ]:to finish|to merely result in something less severe than expected|to feel at ease|
果たして無事で済んでいたかどうか...
Don't say scary things like that.
怖い[こわい]:scary/frightening|(I'm) afraid
怖いことを言うなよ
I'm the one who is scared saying this.
怖い[こわい]:scary/frightening|(I'm) afraid
これを言っていて怖いのは私だよ
To think that Suruga Kanbaru
was the daughter of the Gaen clan...
まさか:by no means/never!|something unexpected, 家[いえ]:house|family|lineage, 家[うち, ち]:house/home (one's own)|(one's) family, 娘[じょう]:unmarried woman|Miss|-ess, 娘[むすめ]:(my) daughter|girl (i.e. a young, unmarried woman)
まさか神原駿河が 臥煙家の娘だったとは
When I think about what would've happened
if I had injured her without
危害を加える[きがいをくわえる]:to harm/to cause harm to
何も知らずに危害を加えていたらと思うと
knowing anything, I start trembling.
身震い[みぶるい]:shivering/trembling/shuddering, 禁ずる[きんずる]:to forbid/to suppress, 得る[うる]:to be able to .../can ...|to get, 得る[える]:to get|to understand|to receive something undesirable (e.g. a punishment)|
身震いを禁じ得ない
I'm glad that I had heard things in advance.
先[さき]:previous|point (e.g. pencil)|head (of a line)||, 先[せん]:former/previous|first move (in go, shogi, etc.)
先に聞いておいて本当によかった
Tadatsuru, so you had heard something
from Gaen-san before you received the request?
正弦[せいげん]:sine, 依頼[いらい]:request/commission|dependence
正弦 お前は依頼が来る前に
臥煙さんから何かを聞いていたってことなのか?
No, it was someone else that was
the middleman between me and Gaen-senpai.
先輩[せんぱい]:senior (at work or school)/superior/elder, 間[あいだ, あわい]:space (between)|time (between)|span (temporal or spatial)||, 間[ま]:time|space|room, 仲立ち[なかだち]:mediation/agency/agent, 別人[べつじん, べつにん]:different person/someone else/changed man
いや 私と臥煙先輩との間を仲立ちしたのは 別人だよ
MIDDLEMAN
To the word "middleman,"
I had one inspiration.
仲立ち[なかだち]:mediation/agency/agent, 言葉[ことば, けとば]:language|word|speech, 直感[ちょっかん]:intuition/instinct/insight, 得る[うる]:to be able to .../can ...|to get, 得る[える]:to get|to understand|to receive something undesirable (e.g. a punishment)|
仲立ち という言葉に ひとつの直感を得た
Oshino?
野[の, や]:plain|hidden (structural) member|wild|
忍野?
OSHINO
Meme Oshino?
野[の, や]:plain|hidden (structural) member|wild|
忍野メメ?
CHAPTER 009
Correct.
名答[めいとう]:correct answer
ご名答
Yes, that man
who acts as he sees through things.
見透かす[みすかす]:to see through/to see the true nature of something
そう あの見透かしたような男が だ
Despite being one of the leading members
of Gaen-senpai's network,
先輩[せんぱい]:senior (at work or school)/superior/elder, ネットワーク:network, 幹部[かんぶ]:management/(executive) staff/leaders, クラス:class, ながら:while/during|while
臥煙先輩のネットワークの幹部クラスでありながら
he reached out and contacted me.
接触[せっしょく]:touch/contact, 取ってくる[とってくる]:to fetch/to go and get
私に接触を取ってくるとは
That made me feel like
he was still a free man as ever.
相変わらず[あいかわらず]:as ever/as usual/the same, 自由自在[じゆうじざい]:free/unrestricted/(with) complete mastery
相変わらず自由自在な男だと思ったよ
He had said that because I was outside
of Gaen-senpai's network,
先輩[せんぱい]:senior (at work or school)/superior/elder, ネットワーク:network, 外[そと, と]:outside|open air|other place, 外[ほか]:other (place, thing, person)|outside|nothing except|
臥煙先輩のネットワークの外にいる私だからこそ
there was something I could do.
ことがある:(something) has occurred/to have done (something)|(something) happens on occasions
できることがあると言っていたね
あいつは
And that was when you had heard
of Kanbaru's background in advance?
際[きわ, ぎわ]:edge/brink|time, 際[さい]:on the occasion of/circumstances/juncture, 出自[しゅつじ]:birthplace|descent|one's outward self, あらかじめ:beforehand/in advance/previously
その際にお前は
神原の出自やらをあらかじめ聞いていたってことか?
Yup. And there was talk about you as well,
or should I say, talk about you guys?
話[はなし]:talk/speech|discussions, 話[わ]:counter for stories, episodes of TV series, etc., 達[たち]:pluralizing suffix (esp. for people & animals; formerly honorific), 達[だち, ダチ]:friend
うん それに きみの話も出た
きみ達の話 と言うべきかな
Now that I think about it, he was appealing to me
about how safe you guys were.
達[たち]:pluralizing suffix (esp. for people & animals; formerly honorific), 達[だち, ダチ]:friend, 安全性[あんぜんせい]:safety/security, アピール:appeal (e.g. to public opinion)/plea/request, してい:servant/janitor/messenger, してい:older sister and younger brother
今から思うと
あいつはきみ達の安全性をアピールしていたんだな
By the way, I realized that he had
ちなみ:association/link|pledge (esp. for marriage), 正体[しょうたい]:true character/true form|consciousness, 人形[にんぎょう]:doll/puppet/figure
ちなみに私の正体が人形だと
seen my true identity as just a doll,
was at that time as well.
見透かす[みすかす]:to see through/to see the true nature of something
あいつが見透かしていたことを知ったのはそのときだった
No, now that I think about it,
maybe he was threatening me?
脅す[おどす]:to threaten/to menace/to bully, しれる:to become known/to come to light|to be known
いや 今から思うと脅されたのかもしれないな?
Like, "if you laid a hand on my friends,
I'll disclose your true nature."
友達[ともだち]:friend/companion, 手を出す[てをだす]:to turn one's hand to|to get involved in|to start a fight, 正体[しょうたい]:true character/true form|consciousness
僕の友達に手を出したら きみの正体をバラすぞ と
TO THINK HE HAD TAKEN COUNTERMEASURES
TO PREPARE FOR A SITUATION THAT IS EXPECTED TO HAPPEN
This was the argument he had made.
言い分[いいぶん]:one's say/one's point|complaint
あいつの言い分はこうだった
"Koyomi Araragi and Shinobu Oshino."
暦[こよみ, れき]:calendar/almanac, 野[の, や]:plain|hidden (structural) member|wild|, 基本的[きほんてき]:fundamental/standard/basic, 無害[むがい]:harmless
"阿良々木暦と忍野忍 彼らは今 基本的には無害だ"
"Currently, they are basically harmless."
"As long as you leave them untouched,
there are no problems."
手を出す[てをだす]:to turn one's hand to|to get involved in|to start a fight, 問題[もんだい]:question (e.g. on a test)|problem (e.g. societal, political)|question (i.e. doubt)||
"手を出さなければ 何も問題はない"
"However, I'm not saying cases
that deviate from the norm don't exist."
ただし:but/however/provided that, 基本[きほん]:foundation/basis/standard, 逸脱[いつだつ]:deviation/departure|omission, ケース:case (e.g. receptacle, condition, event, legal action, letter style, etc.)
"ただし 基本から逸脱するケースがないわけでもない
"The case IS where Araragi-kun colludes with
Shinobu-chan, and continues to vampirify himself."
ちゃんと:diligently/seriously|perfectly, 結託[けったく]:conspiracy/collusion, 吸血鬼[きゅうけつき]:vampire/bloodsucker, 化[か]:action of making something/-ification, 繰り返す[くりかえす]:to repeat/to do something over again, 場合[ばあい]:case/situation
それは阿良々木くんが忍ちゃんと結託し
吸血鬼化を繰り返した場合だ"
In other words, that man was deeply concerned
about the arrival of a situation
得る[うる]:to be able to .../can ...|to get, 得る[える]:to get|to understand|to receive something undesirable (e.g. a punishment)|, 状況[じょうきょう]:state of affairs (around you)/situation/circumstances, 来訪[らいほう]:visit/call, 危惧[きぐ]:apprehensions/misgivings/uneasiness, してい:servant/janitor/messenger, してい:older sister and younger brother
つまり 阿良々木くんがそうせざるを得ないような状況の来訪を
あの男は危惧していた
where you had to do as such, Araragi-kun.
He seemed to know you'd willingly be reckless
when it came to situations of that sort.
状況[じょうきょう]:state of affairs (around you)/situation/circumstances, 際する[さいする]:to arrive/to come to pass, 無茶[むちゃ, むっちゃ]:absurd/unreasonable|very, 厭う[いとう]:to be loath to/to balk at (doing)|to take (good) care of
そういった状況に際して
きみが無茶をすることを厭わないことはわかっていたようだ
Even if he knew...
わかられてもな...
If such turn of events were to happen,
I may receive some sort of a request.
展開[てんかい]:development|expansion|expansion, 際[きわ, ぎわ]:edge/brink|time, 際[さい]:on the occasion of/circumstances/juncture, 依頼[いらい]:request/commission|dependence, しれる:to become known/to come to light|to be known
そういう展開になった際に
私になんらかの依頼が来るかもしれない
吸血鬼[きゅうけつき]:vampire/bloodsucker, 退治[たいじ]:extermination (e.g. of pests, demons, bandits)|making someone renounce worldly desires in order to concentrate on Buddha's teachings|curing illness, 依頼[いらい]:request/commission|dependence
吸血鬼退治の依頼が だ
A request to hunt down vampires, that is.
積年[せきねん]:(many) years|long-standing (esp. hatred, grudge)/ancient, 恨み[うらみ]:resentment/grudge|matter for regret, 忘れる[わすれる]:to forget/to leave carelessly/to be forgetful of, 先輩[せんぱい]:senior (at work or school)/superior/elder, 接点[せってん]:tangent point|contact (electrical, etc.)|point of agreement, 持つ[もつ]:to hold (in one's hand)|to possess|to maintain||
そうなったら積年の恨みを忘れ
臥煙先輩と接点を持ってくれ
He wanted me to "forget my grudges from the past,
and seek contact with Gaen-senpai."
"And at that point, Gaen-senpai
should be waiting to hear from you."
先輩[せんぱい]:senior (at work or school)/superior/elder, 連絡[れんらく]:to contact|contacting|connection|
そのとき 臥煙先輩はきみからの連絡を待っているはずだ
"Because Gaen-senpai can't move,
as she has her position to hold."
立場[たちば]:standpoint/position/situation, 先輩[せんぱい]:senior (at work or school)/superior/elder, 動く[うごく]:to move|to operate|to be touched||
立場のある臥煙先輩からは動けないから
Back then, I didn't really understand
what he was talking about.
そのときは 何を言っているのかよくわからなかったけれど
But in reality, things went exactly
like he thought it would go.
実際[じっさい]:practicality|reality|bhutakoti (limit of reality), 通り[とおり]:avenue|coming and going|flow (of water, air, etc.)||, 通り[どおり]:in accordance with|roughly|Street, 展開[てんかい]:development|expansion|expansion
実際にその通りの展開になったというわけだ
And that's why, when that request came flying in,
indeed, to exterminate you guys,
まさしく:surely/no doubt/evidently, 達[たち]:pluralizing suffix (esp. for people & animals; formerly honorific), 達[だち, ダチ]:friend, 退治[たいじ]:extermination (e.g. of pests, demons, bandits)|making someone renounce worldly desires in order to concentrate on Buddha's teachings|curing illness, 依頼[いらい]:request/commission|dependence, 舞い込む[まいこむ]:to come fluttering in (e.g. leaves, snow, flowers, etc.)/to come dancing in|to drop in unexpectedly
だから 私のところに まさしく
きみ達を退治すべきだという依頼が舞い込んできたとき
it sent shivers up my spine.
ぞっと:shuddering/shivering/trembling
ぞっとしたものだよ
At the same time,
I found it rather strange.
同時[どうじ]:simultaneous/concurrent/same time, 不思議[ふしぎ]:wonder/miracle/strange
と 同時に不思議でもあった
If he was so concerned
about this turn of events,
展開[てんかい]:development|expansion|expansion, 危惧[きぐ]:apprehensions/misgivings/uneasiness, してい:servant/janitor/messenger, してい:older sister and younger brother
この展開を危惧していたのであれば
why didn't Oshino want to do something
about it on his own?
野[の, や]:plain|hidden (structural) member|wild|
どうして忍野は自分でなんとかしようと思わないのだろう
That was something I became intrigued in.
辺り[あたり, ほとり]:on the bank of|(in the) neighbourhood|around (Sunday, last year, etc...)|, 興味[きょうみ]:interest (in something)/curiosity (about something)/zest (for)
その辺りが興味になった
That's why I thought I'd play along
with his little arrangement.
はからい:arrangement/good offices/discretion, 乗る[のる]:to get on (train, plane, bus, ship, etc.)|to get on (e.g. a footstool)|to reach||, ことにする:to make a distinction/to differ/to be different, ことにする:to decide to|to pretend that
だからここはあいつのはからいに乗ってやることにした
I contacted Gaen-senpai.
先輩[せんぱい]:senior (at work or school)/superior/elder, 連絡を取る[れんらくをとる]:to get in touch with
私は臥煙先輩に連絡を取った
AND SO, THE CURTAIN ROSE ON THE FARCE PLAY.
CHAPTER 010
Araragi-san, that's your ride
to go back to the material world.
現世[げんせい, げんせ]:present world/present age|recent epoch (i.e. the Holocene epoch), お迎え[おむかえ]:receiving/welcoming|final call
阿良々木さん あれが現世からのお迎えですよ
You really are running out of time.
なくなる:to die, なくなる:to be lost (e.g. luggage)/to be missing|to be used up
本当に時間がなくなってきてますよ
If you miss that thread, Araragi-san, you really
will continue to burn forever here in Avici.
糸[いと]:thread/yarn/string, 糸[し]:thread|0.001/one ten-thousandth, 逃す[のがす]:to miss (e.g. a chance)|to set free|to fail to ..., 阿鼻[あび]:Avici (lowest level of hell), 地獄[じごく]:hell, 永遠[えいえん]:eternity/perpetuity/immortality, 焼く[やく]:to burn|to roast|to heat||, 続ける[つづける]:to continue/to keep up/to keep on, ことになる:it has been decided (so) that/it has been arranged (so) that|it is the result (of)
あの糸を逃したら
阿良々木さんは本当に阿鼻地獄で永遠に焼かれ続けることになります
And so, Teori-san, I'm terribly sorry,
but can you cut that story out about here?
折[おり]:opportunity|fold|small food box (wooden or cardboard), 申し訳[もうしわけ]:apology/excuse, 話[はなし]:talk/speech|discussions, 話[わ]:counter for stories, episodes of TV series, etc., やめる:to stop (an activity)/to cease|to cancel, やめる:to resign/to retire/to quit, もらう:to receive/to take|to get somebody to do something
というわけで手折さん 申し訳ないんですけれども
もうその話 ここでやめてもらってもいいですか?
No, wait, Hachikuji.
寺[てら]:temple (Buddhist), 寺[じ]:counter for temples
いや待て八九寺
It wasn't okay to just
merely turn down the request?
依頼[いらい]:request/commission|dependence, 普通[ふつう]:general|normally|local train, 断る[ことわる]:to refuse|to inform|to ask leave, 駄目[だめ, ダメ]:no good|hopeless|cannot|
依頼を普通に断るっていうんじゃ駄目だったのか?
"It's better for me to play along
with what the enemy intended."
敵[かたき]:rival|revenge|spouse, 敵[てき]:opponent/rival|menace, 思惑[おもわく]:expectation|purpose|others' opinions of one|, 思惑[しわく]:perceptive mental disturbances, 乗る[のる]:to get on (train, plane, bus, ship, etc.)|to get on (e.g. a footstool)|to reach||
ここは "敵" の思惑に乗っておくのがいい
That was the conclusion
Gaen-senpai and I came to.
先輩[せんぱい]:senior (at work or school)/superior/elder, 結論[けつろん]:conclusion
というのが私と臥煙先輩の出した結論だった
I did say it was better to play along
with what they intended,
思惑[おもわく]:expectation|purpose|others' opinions of one|, 思惑[しわく]:perceptive mental disturbances, 乗る[のる]:to get on (train, plane, bus, ship, etc.)|to get on (e.g. a footstool)|to reach||
思惑に乗っておくのがいいと言ったものの
but their intent is not something
I clearly understand.
思惑[おもわく]:expectation|purpose|others' opinions of one|, 思惑[しわく]:perceptive mental disturbances, はっきり:clearly/plainly|to be clear
その思惑が何なのか
はっきりわかっているわけではない
I'm doing this because
I want to find out what it is.
探る[さぐる]:to feel around for|to investigate|to explore (parts unknown)
それを探りたくてやっていることだ
That, and simultaneously,
同時[どうじ]:simultaneous/concurrent/same time, 吸血鬼[きゅうけつき]:vampire/bloodsucker, 化[か]:action of making something/-ification, 進行[しんこう]:moving forward (e.g. vehicle)|advance (work, procedure, etc)|progress (of a disease)|, 止める[とめる]:to stop|to park|to prevent||, 止める[やめる]:to stop (an activity)/to cease|to cancel, 必要[ひつよう]:necessary/needed|necessity, 処置[しょち]:measure/step|medical treatment, でもある:to also be (formal, literary)/implies that as well as the earlier stated this is also the case|to be ... or something
そしてまた 同時に
きみの吸血鬼化の進行を止めるために必要な処置でもあった
it was a measure necessary in order to stop
progression of you turning into a vampire.
So that I can come to this side
like this, and guide you...
側[そば, そく]:near/close|third person, 側[がわ, かわ]:side (of something, or taking someone's side)/part|(watch) case, 誘導[ゆうどう]:guidance/leading/induction
私がこうして こちら側に来て
きみを誘導するという
Since it was right after
I played a despicable character,
嫌われ者[きらわれもの]:hated person/disliked person/unpopular person, 演ずる[えんずる]:to perform/to play, 直後[ちょくご]:immediately following
嫌われ者を演じた直後のことだったので
I also had to have some assistance
from Hachikuji-chan right there to pull it off.
辺[へん]:area|side|circumstances, 辺[へ, べ]:surrounding area|shore (of the sea)|suffix used as a rough indicator of location, direction, time, etc., 寺[てら]:temple (Buddhist), 寺[じ]:counter for temples, 協力[きょうりょく]:cooperation/collaboration, もらう:to receive/to take|to get somebody to do something, ことになる:it has been decided (so) that/it has been arranged (so) that|it is the result (of)
その辺は そこの八九寺ちゃんにも協力してもらうことになったがね
I was allowed to assist for this.
協力[きょうりょく]:cooperation/collaboration, いただく:to receive/to get|to eat
協力させていただきました
KOYOMI ARARAGI
TADATSURU TEORI
It's in the parenthesis, cameo appearance.
（友情出演）です
It shows up
at the end of the ending credits.
エンド:end, ロール:roll, 最後[さいご]:last|no sooner than|one's final moments
エンドロールの最後のほうに出る奴です
MAYOI HACHIKUJI
(CAMEO APPEARANCE)
So kill once to reset, and resurrect just
the "human" part of my physical body, huh?
いったん:once|for a short time/briefly, いったん:one end/an end|part, リセット:reset, 肉体[にくたい]:the body/the flesh, 部分[ぶぶん]:portion/section/part, 生き返る[いきかえる]:to revive/to come to oneself/to be restored to life
いったん殺してリセットして
僕の肉体の "人間" の部分だけを生き返らせる か
IF SO, THEN, IT WOULD'VE BEEN NICE
IF THEY TOLD ME IN ADVANCE,
BUT IF THEY DIDN'T TELL ME, THAT MEANS
THERE WERE CIRCUMSTANCES
PREVENTING THEM FROM TELLING ME IN ADVANCE
THAT PART MAY BE THE TACTIC
THEY ARE TAKING AGAINST THE ENEMY
THERE'S NO WAY FOR ME TO KNOW FROM MY VIEWPOINT.
Of course, if we were to use the demon sword
"Yume Watari" to revive you
もっとも:most/extremely, もっとも:but then/although|reasonable, 妖刀[ようとう]:bewitched sword/magical sword/demon sword, 夢[ゆめ]:dream, 生き返る[いきかえる]:to revive/to come to oneself/to be restored to life
もっとも 妖刀 "心渡" で殺したきみを
妖刀 "夢渡" で生き返らせたら
after killing you with
the demon sword "Kokoro Watari,"
it may revive you
just the way you were, as a vampire.
吸血鬼[きゅうけつき]:vampire/bloodsucker, 生き返る[いきかえる]:to revive/to come to oneself/to be restored to life, かねる:to be unable to/to find difficult (unpleasant, awkward, painful) to do|to serve two or more functions or roles simultaneously
吸血鬼としてのきみがそのまま生き返りかねなくて
That would have put us back
at square one.
元[もと]:origin|base|cause||, 元[げん]:unknown (e.g. in an equation)|element (of a set)|yuan (monetary unit of China)|
それでは元の木阿弥(もくあみ)だからね
In order to not do that, we needed me
地獄[じごく]:hell, 側[そば, そく]:near/close|third person, 側[がわ, かわ]:side (of something, or taking someone's side)/part|(watch) case
そうしないために地獄側から
to interfere as a specialist
over from the hell side of things.
専門家[せんもんか]:specialist/expert/professional, 横入り[よこはいり, よこいり]:cutting in line/queue jumping, 必要[ひつよう]:necessary/needed|necessity
私という専門家の横入りが必要になったというわけだ
Without making that correction, there was
nothing we could do against the enemy.
点[ちょぼ, チョボ]:dot/point|gidayuu musicians (in kabuki), 点[てん]:spot|point|mark (e.g. in exam)||, 修正[しゅうせい]:amendment/correction/revision, 敵[かたき]:rival|revenge|spouse, 敵[てき]:opponent/rival|menace, 対する[たいする]:to face (each other)|to be directed toward (the future, etc.)|to receive (a client, etc.)||, 打つ[うつ]:to hit|to strike (noon, etc.)|to beat (rhythmically, e.g. pulse, waves, etc.)||, 打つ[ぶつ]:to hit (a person)/to strike/to beat
その点を修正しないことには
敵に対して手の打ちようがないというのも
That was the mutual conclusion
that both Gaen-senpai and I came to.
先輩[せんぱい]:senior (at work or school)/superior/elder, 共通[きょうつう]:commonness|to be common|-wide, 結論[けつろん]:conclusion
私と臥煙先輩の共通した結論だ
Let us be on our way, Araragi-san.
行きましょうよ 阿良々木さん
This thing is alive.
生きる[いきる]:to live|to make a living|to be in effect||
生きてんじゃねえかよ
Come to think, I hadn't asked yet.
そう言えば まだ聞いてなかったな
Yes?
はい?
I was supposedly slain at
North Shirahebi Shrine in the real world.
現世[げんせい, げんせ]:present world/present age|recent epoch (i.e. the Holocene epoch), 北[きた]:north|the North|North Korea|, 北[ペー]:north wind tile|winning hand with a pung (or kong) of north wind tiles, 白蛇[しろへび, はくじゃ]:albino Japanese rat snake, 神社[じんじゃ]:Shinto shrine, 斬る[きる]:to kill (a human) using a blade (sword, machete, knife, etc.)/to slice (off)/to lop (off), 地獄[じごく]:hell, 公園[こうえん]:(public) park, 目覚める[めざめる]:to wake up|to awaken to (instinct, ability, perception, etc.)|to come to one's senses
どうして現世で 北白蛇神社で斬られたはずの僕が
地獄ではあの公園で目覚めたんだ?
Why did I wake up
in that park over in hell?
That bothers you that much?
気になる[きになる]:to be on one's mind|to feel like|to fancy
それ そんなに気になりますか?
It's not enough to bother me per se, but...
気になる[きになる]:to be on one's mind|to feel like|to fancy
気になるというほどでもないが
NO.
I KNOW. I'M JUST DELAYING.
TO CLIMB THIS WHITE SNAKE—
TO RESURRECT BACK INTO LIFE.
I'M DELAYING IT FURTHER AND FURTHER
PARK
About the shift, well, I don't care.
云々[うんぬん]:and so on/and so forth|comment
ズレ云々は まあどうでもいいや
But, if you know what the name
of that park is, I'd like to know.
公園[こうえん]:(public) park, 教える[おしえる]:to teach|to tell|to preach, 欲しい[ほしい]:wanted/wished for|I want (you) to
だけど あの公園の名前を 知ってるって言うんなら
教えて欲しいもんだ
NAMISHIRO
Is it "Namishiro," or "Rouhaku"?
なみする:to set at naught/to ignore/to disregard
"なみしろ" なんだか "ろうはく" なんだか
"Shirohebi" Park.
公園[こうえん]:(public) park
しろへび公園
The correct way to read the name
is "Shirohebi" Park, if you go back to its origin.
公園[こうえん]:(public) park, 読む[よむ]:to read|to count|to guess, 正しい[ただしい]:right/correct|proper, 元を糺す[もとをただす]:to go to the bottom of an affair/to inquire into the origin
しろへび公園と読むのが正しい 元を糺せば
Eh? Shirohebi?
え? しろへび?
HEBI
(SNAKE)
It's not the "insect" radical,
but the "water" radical.
虫偏[むしへん]:kanji "insect" radical at left, さんずい:kanji "water" radical (radical 85), 偏[へん]:left-hand radical of a character
虫偏ではなくさんずい偏だよ
HEBI
Shirohebi.
沱白
SHIROHEBI
Somewhere along the way,
someone miswrote and HEBI turned into NAMI.
書き間違える[かきまちがえる]:to write incorrectly (e.g. character)/to make a mistake in writing, 浪[なみ]:wave, 難読[なんどく]:difficult to read (e.g. obscure kanji), 理由[りゆう, わけ]:reason/pretext/motive
どこかで書き間違えられて
"沱" が "浪" になったのが 難読になった理由だよ
It's why the location became hard to read.
HEBI
NAMI
Wait, "shirohebi"...
白蛇[しろへび, はくじゃ]:albino Japanese rat snake
白蛇って...
...North "Shirahebi" Shrine.
北[きた]:north|the North|North Korea|, 北[ペー]:north wind tile|winning hand with a pung (or kong) of north wind tiles, 白蛇[しろへび, はくじゃ]:albino Japanese rat snake, 神社[じんじゃ]:Shinto shrine
北... 白蛇神社
NORTH SHIRAHEBI SHRINE
Yup. That's what it means.
元々[もともと]:originally/by nature/from the start, 北[きた]:north|the North|North Korea|, 北[ペー]:north wind tile|winning hand with a pung (or kong) of north wind tiles, 白蛇[しろへび, はくじゃ]:albino Japanese rat snake, 神社[じんじゃ]:Shinto shrine, あそこ:there (place physically distant from both speaker and listener)/over there|genitals
うん そういうことだ
元々北白蛇神社は あそこにあったんだよ
Originally, North Shirahebi Shrine
used to be at that location.
That's why that slight shift occurred.
ズレる:to slide/to slip off/to get dislocated
だからズレた
You've heard the story that this shrine
was one that had been relocated, perhaps?
神社[じんじゃ]:Shinto shrine, 移築[いちく]:dismantling an historic building and reconstructing it elsewhere, 話[はなし]:talk/speech|discussions, 話[わ]:counter for stories, episodes of TV series, etc.
この神社が移築されたものであるという話は
聞いたことが... あるかな?
Yeah, that's—
ああ それは...
I think it was a mistake in connection,
確か[たしか]:sure|reliable|If I'm not mistaken, 接続[せつぞく]:connection|changing trains|conjunction, 歪み[ひずみ, ゆがみ]:strain/distortion/deformation, 原因[げんいん]:cause/origin/source
確か接続ミスであり
歪みの原因にもなったとか なんとか...
and became a reason for distortion,
or something.
Right, as it was something like bringing
the god of the seas on top of a mountain.
海[うみ, み]:sea/ocean/waters, 持つ[もつ]:to hold (in one's hand)|to possess|to maintain||
そうだね 海の神を山に持ってきたようなものなんだから
Though, to be precise, it wasn't a sea but a lake.
厳密[げんみつ]:strict/close, 海[うみ, み]:sea/ocean/waters, 湖[みずうみ]:lake, 湖[こ]:lake (in place names)
厳密には海ではなく 湖 だが
Lake? I think I've heard about that
from someone at some point...
湖[みずうみ]:lake, 湖[こ]:lake (in place names)
湖? それも どこかで誰かに聞いたような...
Well, you should
get on your way soon, Araragi-kun.
そろそろ:slowly/quietly|soon, 出発[しゅっぱつ]:departure
じゃあ そろそろ出発しようか阿良々木くん
Please give my regards
to Gaen-senpai. And to Yotsugi.
先輩[せんぱい]:senior (at work or school)/superior/elder, よろしく:well/properly|best regards, 余接[よせつ]:cotangent
臥煙先輩によろしく そして余接によろしく
Please cherish Yotsugi on my behalf as well.
余接[よせつ]:cotangent, 可愛い[かわいい, かわゆい]:cute|dear|cute little
私の分まで余接を可愛がってやってくれ
Yeah, got it.
ああ わかった
But is it all right
for someone like me to resurrect?
なんか:things like .../or something like that ... (often derogatory), なんか:something, 生き返る[いきかえる]:to revive/to come to oneself/to be restored to life
でも 僕なんかが生き返っていいのかな
CHAPTER 011
Hachikuji!
寺[てら]:temple (Buddhist), 寺[じ]:counter for temples
八九寺!
"Is it all right
for someone like me to resurrect?"
なんか:things like .../or something like that ... (often derogatory), なんか:something, 生き返る[いきかえる]:to revive/to come to oneself/to be restored to life, なんという:how (beautiful, etc.), 言い草[いいぐさ]:remarks|way of talking|excuse|
僕なんかが生き返っていいのかなとは
なんという言い草ですか
What kind of a statement is that?
What, Araragi-san.
Are you chickening out?
怖気[おぞけ]:fear/dread/fright
なんですか 阿良々木さん
怖気づきましたか
You don't want
to go through difficult ordeals?
大変[たいへん]:very|immense|serious||, 思い[おもい]:thought|imagination|desire||
大変な思いとかしたくないですか
Are you tired of it all?
疲れる[つかれる]:to get tired|to be worn out (e.g. of well used objects)|to starve
疲れちゃいましたか
No.
いや
There really was a feeling
like a tense thread snapping.
張りつめる[はりつめる]:to strain/to stretch/to string up, 糸[いと]:thread/yarn/string, 糸[し]:thread|0.001/one ten-thousandth, 切れる[きれる]:to break|to be injured|to wear out||, 気持ち[きもち]:feeling|preparedness|thanks|, 確か[たしか]:sure|reliable|If I'm not mistaken
張りつめていた糸が切れたような気持ちは
確かにあって
I didn't really have the feeling of
"I was finally able to die," either.
やっと:at last/at length|barely, 気持ち[きもち]:feeling|preparedness|thanks|
"やっと死ねた" って気持ちも
ないじゃあないんだ
You can only say that because
you don't know the hardships of hell.
地獄[じごく]:hell, 苦しい[くるしい]:painful|needy|forced (smile, joke)||, 言える[いえる]:to be possible to say/to be able to say
地獄の苦しさを知らないからそんなことを言えるんですよ?
You really are quite fortunate
merely because you can be resurrected.
生き返る[いきかえる]:to revive/to come to oneself/to be restored to life, 相当[そうとう]:befitting|considerable|to be worthy of||, 幸運[こううん]:good luck/fortune
生き返れるというだけで
本当 相当な幸運だというのに
FORTUNATE
But I feel like there are tons of other people
who deserve to be resurrected more than me.
他[ほか]:other (place, thing, person)|outside|nothing except|, 他[た]:other (esp. people and abstract matters), 生き返る[いきかえる]:to revive/to come to oneself/to be restored to life, もっと:(some) more/even more/longer
なんていうか... 僕じゃなくて
他に生き返るべき奴はもっといると思うのに
Is it all right for me to be resurrected?
生き返る[いきかえる]:to revive/to come to oneself/to be restored to life, 気持ち[きもち]:feeling|preparedness|thanks|
僕が生き返っていいのかって気持ちかな
It's not that I don't want to be resurrected,
but I feel I'm cutting in line when I shouldn't be.
生き返る[いきかえる]:to revive/to come to oneself/to be restored to life, いける:to arrange (flowers)/to plant|living, いける:to be good (at)/to go well|to look (taste, etc.) good, 順番[じゅんばん]:turn (in line)/order of things/sequential order, 抜く[ぬく]:to extract|to do something to the end|to surpass||, 気分[きぶん]:feeling/mood
生き返りたくないってわけじゃあないんだけれど
やっちゃいけない順番抜かしをしている気分になる
You do, indeed!
ありますよ
You have the right to be resurrected.
生き返る[いきかえる]:to revive/to come to oneself/to be restored to life, 資格[しかく]:qualifications/requirements/capabilities
生き返る資格は あります
Araragi-san, you have at least
that much of a qualification.
くらい:dark/gloomy|dark (in colour), くらい:approximately/about|to (about) the extent that, 資格[しかく]:qualifications/requirements/capabilities
それくらいの資格は阿良々木さんにはあります
Because you've done
at least that much to begin with!
くらい:dark/gloomy|dark (in colour), くらい:approximately/about|to (about) the extent that, してき:historic/historical, してき:pointing out/identification
だってそれくらいのことはしてきたじゃないですか!
Yes, you have. I know all too well!
してき:historic/historical, してき:pointing out/identification, わたし:I/me|private affairs, わたし:ferry (crossing)/ferry(boat)|delivery
ええ してきましたとも
わたしがようく知っています!
If you're not being resurrected,
who are you saying should be resurrected?
生き返る[いきかえる]:to revive/to come to oneself/to be restored to life
あなたが生き返らなきゃ誰が生き返るって言うんですか
Without a doubt,
you are the first person in line!
文句[もんく]:complaint/grumbling|phrase, 一番[いちばん]:number one|best|game||, 一番[ひとつがい]:pair/couple/brace
文句なく あなたが一番手ですよ!
If you say weak-minded things so much,
I might end up hating you.
あんまり:remainder/rest|not very (with negative sentence), 弱気[よわき]:timid/weak-kneed|bearish (e.g. market), ばかり:only/merely|approximately, 嫌い[きらい]:dislike|suspicion|distinction, 嫌い[ぎらい]:dislike/hatred/fear, しまう:to finish/to stop|to close (a business, etc.)
あんまり弱気なことばかり言っていると
嫌いになってしまいますよ
Listen up, Araragi-san.
いいですか 阿良々木さん
The Araragi-san that I know...
わたし:I/me|private affairs, わたし:ferry (crossing)/ferry(boat)|delivery
わたしの知る阿良々木さんは...
loves girls, loves young girls, loves little girls,
loves the skirt linings, loves women's hips,
少女[しょうじょ, おとめ]:little girl/maiden|female between 17 and 20 years old (ritsuryo period), 好き[すき]:liking/fondness/love, 好き[ずき]:-phil/-phile|being attractive (to), 幼女[ようじょ]:little girl, 童女[どうじょ, どうにょ]:(little) girl, スカート:skirt, 裏地[うらじ]:lining|land that does not adjoin to public or private roads, 女子[じょし, おなご]:woman/girl, 女子[めこ, メコ]:vagina|girl, 腰[こし, コシ]:back/lower back|body (of hair, noodle, paper, etc.), 腰[ごし]:posture/position/pose
少女が好きで 幼女が好きで 童女が好きで スカートの裏地が好きで 女子の腰つきが好きで
loves big boobs, loves to be handled roughly,
loves his older little sister,
大きな[おおきな]:big/large/great, おっぱい:breasts/boobies|breast milk, 好き[すき]:liking/fondness/love, 好き[ずき]:-phil/-phile|being attractive (to), 雑[ざつ]:rough/crude|miscellaneous, 雑[ぞう]:miscellany (classification of Japanese poetry unrelated to the seasons or to love), 扱う[あつかう]:to deal with (a person)|to deal with (a problem)|to operate (e.g. a machine)||, 妹[いもうと]:younger sister, 妹[いも]:darling (only of a woman)|one's sister|friend
大きなおっぱいが好きで 雑に扱われるのが好きで 大きな妹が好きで
loves his younger little sister, loves mature women,
loves toplessness, loves bloomers,
小さな[ちいさな]:small/little/tiny, 妹[いもうと]:younger sister, 妹[いも]:darling (only of a woman)|one's sister|friend, 好き[すき]:liking/fondness/love, 好き[ずき]:-phil/-phile|being attractive (to), 熟女[じゅくじょ]:attractive mature lady, 上半身[じょうはんしん]:upper half of body/bust, 裸[はだか]:naked/nude/bare, ブルマ:long female underwear (from bloomers)
小さな妹が好きで 熟女が好きで 上半身裸が好きで ブルマが好きで
loves school-issued swimsuits,
loves class reps,
スクール:school, 水着[みずぎ]:bathing suit/swimsuit/swimmers, 好き[すき]:liking/fondness/love, 好き[ずき]:-phil/-phile|being attractive (to), 委員長[いいんちょう]:committee chairman
スクール水着が好きで 委員長が好きで
loves girls who use "boku,"
loves cat ears, loves girls playing sports...
っ子[っこ]:someone with a liking or characteristic/a true representative of (place), 好き[すき]:liking/fondness/love, 好き[ずき]:-phil/-phile|being attractive (to), 猫耳[ねこみみ]:cat ears, スポーツ:sport/sports, 少女[しょうじょ, おとめ]:little girl/maiden|female between 17 and 20 years old (ritsuryo period)
僕っ子が好きで 猫耳が好きで スポーツ少女が好きで
Hold on a second.
ちょっと待って
Hold it, hold it, hold it, hold it!
待って待って待って待って
My heart is about to completely snap right now.
そろそろ:slowly/quietly|soon, ぽっきり:merely/having just ..., 折れる[おれる]:to break|to be folded|to give in|
心がそろそろぽっきり折れそうなんだけれど
And you were someone who loves to be alive.
生きる[いきる]:to live|to make a living|to be in effect||, 大好き[だいすき]:loveable/very likeable/like very much
生きるのが大好きな人だったじゃないですか
IT WAS SO OBVIOUS THAT I HAD FORGOTTEN.
I CAME TO THE BRINK OF DEATH MANY, MANY TIMES—
AND EACH TIME, I NARROWLY ESCAPED DEATH
BECAUSE OF THAT, I HAD COMPLETELY FORGOTTEN.
You're right.
そうだよな...
If I'm not alive, I can't cherish girls at all.
生きる[いきる]:to live|to make a living|to be in effect||, 少女[しょうじょ, おとめ]:little girl/maiden|female between 17 and 20 years old (ritsuryo period), 愛でる[めでる]:to love/to admire
生きていなければ
少女を愛(め)でることもできないものな
Uhm, no, that's not exactly
what I wanted to tell you.
わたし:I/me|private affairs, わたし:ferry (crossing)/ferry(boat)|delivery
あ いえ
わたしが言いたかったのはそういうことではないんですけれども
To say there was a shift
in the meaning of life...
生きる[いきる]:to live|to make a living|to be in effect||, 意味[いみ]:meaning/significance, ブレる:to be blurred (photo, video, etc.)|to waver (in one's beliefs, policy, etc.)|to shift (position), なんて:how ..!/what ..!|what (questioning), なんて:such as/(things) like|exclamation
生きる意味がブレるなんてよく言ったもんだ...
There was plenty of meaning
merely by staying alive.
生きる[いきる]:to live|to make a living|to be in effect||, 十分[じっぷん, じゅっぷん]:10 minutes, 十分[じゅうぶん]:plenty|division into ten|perfectly, 意味[いみ]:meaning/significance
生きてるだけで
十分に意味はあったじゃないか
If you love being alive,
that's all you really needed.
生きる[いきる]:to live|to make a living|to be in effect||, 好き[すき]:liking/fondness/love, 好き[ずき]:-phil/-phile|being attractive (to)
生きてることが好きなら それだけでよかった
Because I was able to love
all sorts of things, and people.
色んな[いろんな]:various, 物[もの, もん]:thing|one's things|things||, 物[ぶつ, ブツ]:stock/products|stolen goods, 好き[すき]:liking/fondness/love, 好き[ずき]:-phil/-phile|being attractive (to)
色んな物を 色んな人を好きになれたんだから
When you say that in this context,
it may be a bit misleading.
文脈[ぶんみゃく]:context, いささか:a little/a bit/somewhat, 語弊がある[ごへいがある]:to be misleading
この文脈で言うといささか語弊(ごへい)がありそうですけれどね
If I give the signal from this end, Gaen-senpai
will pull you up from her end. That's about it.
こちら:this way (direction close to the speaker or towards the speaker)/this direction|here (place close to the speaker or where the speaker is), 合図[あいず]:sign/signal, 送る[おくる]:to send (a thing)|to take or escort (a person somewhere)|to bid farewell (to the departed)||, あちら:that way (direction distant from both speaker and listener)/over there|that one (something physically distant from both speaker and listener, or something not visible but known by both speaker and listener), 先輩[せんぱい]:senior (at work or school)/superior/elder, 引っ張る[ひっぱる]:to pull|to string (lines)|to pull towards oneself (e.g. someone's sleeve)||, 上げる[あげる]:to raise|to do up (one's hair)|to fly (a kite, etc.)||, イメージ:(one's) image
私がこちらから合図を送れば
あちらから臥煙先輩が引っ張り上げてくれるイメージだ
Got it.
わかった
I'm much obliged, Tadatsuru.
世話になる[せわになる]:to receive favor (favour)/to be much obliged to someone/to be indebted, 正弦[せいげん]:sine
世話になったな 正弦
Tadatsuru-san.
正弦[せいげん]:sine
...正弦さん
No need to be formal
after all we've been through.
今更[いまさら]:now (after such a long time)/at this late hour (i.e. it is too late for something)|afresh, 畏まる[かしこまる]:to obey respectfully/to humble oneself/to sit straight (upright, respectfully, attentively)
今更 畏(かしこ)まることはないよ
As long as you continue to attempt protecting
Kiss-shot Acerola-orion Heart-under-blade,
アセロラオリオン:acerola (Malpighia glabra)/Barbados cherry, アセロラオリオン:Orion, ハート:heart, アンダー:under, ブレード:blade, 保護[ほご, ほうご]:care/protection/shelter, 続ける[つづける]:to continue/to keep up/to keep on, 限り[かぎり]:limit|degree|as far as possible||, 限り[きり]:end|bounds|delivery date (of a futures contract)||
きみがキスショット・アセロラオリオン・ハートアンダーブレードを
保護しようとし続ける限り
...you will be my enemy.
敵[かたき]:rival|revenge|spouse, 敵[てき]:opponent/rival|menace
きみは私の敵だよ
Even then, I'm much obliged
for this particular case.
今回[こんかい]:now/this time/lately, 世話になる[せわになる]:to receive favor (favour)/to be much obliged to someone/to be indebted
それでも 今回のことでは世話になった
I never thought I'd be able
to chat with you like this.
風[ふり]:swing|appearance|pretence (pretense)||, 風[かぜ]:wind|manner|cold, 話せる[はなせる]:to be able to speak/to be able to talk|to be understanding, なんて:how ..!/what ..!|what (questioning), なんて:such as/(things) like|exclamation
お前とこんな風に話せるだなんて思ってなかったから
Someday, when we have time,
I'd like to settle down and talk with you again.
腰を落ち着ける[こしをおちつける]:to settle down, 話す[はなす]:to talk|to tell|to speak (a language)
いつか時間があるときに
もうちょっと腰を落ち着けて話したい
If you don't mind doing so
while we kill each other.
殺し合う[ころしあう]:to kill each other, ながら:while/during|while
殺し合いながらでもよければ
Hachikuji.
What are you going to do from here?
寺[てら]:temple (Buddhist), 寺[じ]:counter for temples
八九寺 お前は これからどうするんだ?
What?
はい?
Me? After I see you off, Araragi-san,
わたし:I/me|private affairs, わたし:ferry (crossing)/ferry(boat)|delivery, 見送る[みおくる]:to see someone off (at a station, an airport, etc.)|to follow something with one's eyes until it is out of sight|to let pass||, 賽の河原[さいのかわら]:Children's Limbo|futile/unrewarding, 戻る[もどる]:to turn back (e.g. half-way)|to return|to recover (e.g. something lost)|, 戻る[もとる]:to go against/to act contrary to/to deviate from, 石積み[いしづみ]:masonry/stonework, 毎日[まいにち]:every day
わたしですか? わたしは 阿良々木さんを見送ったら
賽の河原に戻って石積みの毎日ですよ
I'm going back to the banks of hell
to pile stones up every day.
Perhaps I may reincarnate as the child
of you and Senjougahara-san.
ひょっと:possibly/perhaps|unintentionally, 子供[こども]:child/children, 転生[てんせい, てんしょう]:transmigration of souls/reincarnation, ことになる:it has been decided (so) that/it has been arranged (so) that|it is the result (of), しれる:to become known/to come to light|to be known
ひょっとすると阿良々木さんと戦場ヶ原さんの子供として
転生することになるかもしれませんね
That's pretty heavy.
重い[おもい]:heavy|heavy (feeling)|slow||
それは重いな
Now then.
では
I'm good. Send me off at any time.
送る[おくる]:to send (a thing)|to take or escort (a person somewhere)|to bid farewell (to the departed)||
いいぜ いつでも送ってくれ
Then, let's countdown.
カウントダウン:countdown
じゃあ カウントダウン で行くよ
10... 9...
8...
7...
6...
5...
4... 3...
2...
1...
Ignition.
点火[てんか]:ignition/lighting/set fire to, 点火[とぼし]:light/lamp
点火(イグニション)
That's right. Hachikuji said the first person
who should be resurrected is me.
寺[てら]:temple (Buddhist), 寺[じ]:counter for temples, 生き返る[いきかえる]:to revive/to come to oneself/to be restored to life, 一番[いちばん]:number one|best|game||, 一番[ひとつがい]:pair/couple/brace
そうだ 八九寺は生き返るべき一番手は僕だと言ってくれたけれど
But, at the least, I am being
resurrected by shoving Hachikuji aside.
少ない[すくない]:few/a little/scarce, 寺[てら]:temple (Buddhist), 寺[じ]:counter for temples, さしおく:to leave as is/to let alone/to disregard, 生き返る[いきかえる]:to revive/to come to oneself/to be restored to life, しまう:to finish/to stop|to close (a business, etc.)
少なくとも 八九寺をさしおいて
僕は生き返ってしまうのだ
To part with Mayoi Hachikuji...
寺[てら]:temple (Buddhist), 寺[じ]:counter for temples, 別れる[わかれる]:to part (usu. of people)|to separate (of a couple)|to lose (e.g. one's mother)
八九寺真宵と別れるのは...
How many times does this make?
何度[なんど]:how many times?/how often?
これで何度目になるのだろう
H-Hachikuji!
寺[てら]:temple (Buddhist), 寺[じ]:counter for temples
は 八九寺い!
Oh, Araragi-kun, one more thing!
ああ 阿良々木くん ひとつだけ!
I'll tell you the name of the "enemy"
who requested me to exterminate you!
退治[たいじ]:extermination (e.g. of pests, demons, bandits)|making someone renounce worldly desires in order to concentrate on Buddha's teachings|curing illness, 依頼[いらい]:request/commission|dependence, 敵[かたき]:rival|revenge|spouse, 敵[てき]:opponent/rival|menace, 教える[おしえる]:to teach|to tell|to preach
私に 退治を依頼した
"敵" の名前を 私から教えておこう!
Ougi.
扇[おうぎ, おおぎ]:folding fan
扇
Ougi Oshino.
野[の, や]:plain|hidden (structural) member|wild|, 扇[おうぎ, おおぎ]:folding fan
忍野扇
CHAPTER 012
This is the epilogue,
or the punch line for this episode.
後日談[ごじつだん]:sequel/later development, 今回[こんかい]:now/this time/lately
後日談というか 今回のオチ
Really...
まったく:really/truly|indeed
まったく...
To bring Hachikuji-chan with you, Koyomin.
寺[てら]:temple (Buddhist), 寺[じ]:counter for temples, 連れてくる[つれてくる]:to bring someone along, なんて:how ..!/what ..!|what (questioning), なんて:such as/(things) like|exclamation, こよみ:calendar/almanac
八九寺ちゃんを連れてくるだなんて こよみん
You always are someone who goes
way beyond any of my expectations.
期待[きたい]:expectation/anticipation/hope, 遥か[はるか]:far/far away/distant, 超える[こえる]:to cross over/to cross|to exceed
きみって奴はいつだって私の期待を遥かに超えてくれるものだ
But for now, Koyomin,
とりあえず:first of all/at once|for now, こよみ:calendar/almanac
とりあえずこよみん
can you please ask this scary,
beautiful lady to pull back her claws?
怖い[こわい]:scary/frightening|(I'm) afraid, 美女[びじょ]:beautiful woman, 爪[つめ]:nail (e.g. fingernail, toenail)|plectrum|hook, 引っ込める[ひっこめる]:to draw in/to take in|to withdraw, 願う[ねがう]:to desire|to beg|to have something done for oneself
この怖い美女に
爪を引っ込めてくれるようお願いしてくれないかな?
Hey, you.
様[ざま]:mess|-ways|in the act of ...|, 様[さま]:Mr.|makes words more polite (usu. in fixed expressions)|state
よう お前様
Hmph. Well, I guess both needless killings
and futile gashes have been avoided.
無駄[むだ]:futility/uselessness/pointlessness, 殺生[せっしょう]:killing/destruction of life|barbarous, 無益[むえき]:useless/futile/vain, 切傷[きりきず]:cut/gash/incision, 済む[すむ]:to finish|to merely result in something less severe than expected|to feel at ease|
まあ 無駄な殺生(せっしょう)も
無益な切傷もせずには済んだか のう
Though, it was the first time for me
to see "Yume Watari" activate.
夢[ゆめ]:dream, 発動[はつどう]:putting into operation|invocation, 初めて[はじめて]:for the first time|only after ... is it .../only when ... do you ..., じゃう:to do something completely
"夢渡" の発動を見るのは初めてじゃったが...
You fool, you made me worry.
阿呆[あほう, あほ]:fool/simpleton/idiot, 心配[しんぱい]:worry/concern|care
阿呆(あほう)が 心配させおって
And, you abducted a young girl from hell.
You really are reckless.
しかも:moreover/furthermore|nevertheless, 少女[しょうじょ, おとめ]:little girl/maiden|female between 17 and 20 years old (ritsuryo period), ひとり:one person|alone/unmarried, ひとり:incense burner|utensil for carrying live charcoal, 地獄[じごく]:hell, かどわかす:to kidnap, 無茶苦茶[むちゃくちゃ, ムチャクチャ]:nonsensical|awfully|disorder|
しかも 少女をひとり地獄からかどわかしてくるとは
無茶苦茶じゃのう
Hey, Shinobu. This is really bad
no matter how you think about it, right?
考える[かんがえる]:to think about|to ponder|to intend||, まずい:poor-quality/shoddy|unskillful, まずい:unappetising/unappetizing|unskillful
なあ忍 これって
どう考えてもまずいよな...
Did once again, Hachikuji fulfill the conditions
for the "darkness" to be triggered?
寺[てら]:temple (Buddhist), 寺[じ]:counter for temples, くらやみ:darkness/the dark, 発動[はつどう]:putting into operation|invocation, 条件を満たす[じょうけんをみたす]:to meet the requirements/to satisfy the conditions, しまう:to finish/to stop|to close (a business, etc.)
これでまた 八九寺は "くらやみ" の
発動条件を満たしてしまったんじゃ...
And I'm saying that's why
you made a fine play, Koyomin.
こよみ:calendar/almanac, ファインプレー:fine play
そこがこよみんのファインプレーだと言っている
Thanks to Koyomin's miracle here,
こよみ:calendar/almanac, ミラクル:miracle, お蔭[おかげ]:grace (of God)|assistance|effects, 先[さき]:previous|point (e.g. pencil)|head (of a line)||, 先[せん]:former/previous|first move (in go, shogi, etc.), 勝負[しょうぶ]:victory or defeat/match/contest, いくら:how much?/how many?|even, 優位[ゆうい]:predominance/ascendancy/superiority, 進める[すすめる]:to advance/to promote/to hasten
こよみんのミラクルのお蔭で
ここから先の勝負をいくらか優位に進められそうだよ
it looks like we'll be able to take
a slight advantage in the battles to come.
The lost girl.
She's a pawn that I had been wanting.
迷子[まいご]:lost child/lost person/stray child, 少女[しょうじょ, おとめ]:little girl/maiden|female between 17 and 20 years old (ritsuryo period), 欲しい[ほしい]:wanted/wished for|I want (you) to, 駒[こま]:piece (in shogi, chess, etc.)|horse|bridge (of a violin, etc.)
迷子の少女 欲しかった駒(こま)だよ
But with how things are turning out,
以上[いじょう]:not less than|beyond ... (e.g. one's means)|above-mentioned||, 少し[すこし]:small quantity|little while|short distance, 協力[きょうりょく]:cooperation/collaboration, 要請[ようせい]:appeal/call for something|axiom
しかしこうなった以上
私はもう少しだけ協力を要請しなければならないだろうね
it looks like I must request help
for a little while longer.
For now, Koyomin, I want you
to head over to your entrance exams.
とりあえず:first of all/at once|for now, こよみ:calendar/almanac, 受験[じゅけん]:taking an examination (esp. school and university entrance), 向かう[むかう]:to face|to go towards/to head towards, もらう:to receive/to take|to get somebody to do something
とりあえずは こよみんには受験に向かってもらおうか
If you head over now, you'll still make it.
余裕[よゆう]:surplus/margin|composure, 間に合う[まにあう]:to be in time for|to serve (suit, meet) the purpose/to be good enough
今からなら余裕で間に合うだろう
Do your best.
頑張る[がんばる]:to persevere|to insist that|to remain in a place
頑張ってね
Well, I will do my best.
頑張る[がんばる]:to persevere|to insist that|to remain in a place
ま まあ 頑張りますけれど
Koyomin, I'll have you working for me
starting tomorrow.
こよみ:calendar/almanac, 明日[あした, あす]:tomorrow|near future, 動く[うごく]:to move|to operate|to be touched||, もらう:to receive/to take|to get somebody to do something, ことにする:to make a distinction/to differ/to be different, ことにする:to decide to|to pretend that
こよみんには明日から動いてもらうことにする
Everything will be over
before the graduation ceremony.
なあに:what|what?, 卒業式[そつぎょうしき]:graduation ceremony/graduation exercises, 終わる[おわる]:to finish/to end/to close
なあに 卒業式までにはすべて 終わっているよ
I have all of my weapons now.
武器[ぶき]:weapon/arms|weapon (something used to gain an advantage), 揃う[そろう]:to become complete|to be equal|to gather
武器は揃(そろ)った
Let's settle the score, Koyomin.
決着をつける[けっちゃくをつける]:to settle (a dispute), こよみ:calendar/almanac
決着をつけようじゃないか こよみん
Strangely enough, tomorrow is White Day, right?
奇しくも[くしくも]:strangely/oddly/miraculously, 明日[あした, あす]:tomorrow|near future, ホワイトデー:White Day (March 14th)
奇(く)しくも明日はホワイトデーじゃあないか
It's the perfect timing to end the story of this town,
where a white snake once reigned.
かつて:once/before|never yet, 白蛇[しろへび, はくじゃ]:albino Japanese rat snake, 君臨[くんりん]:reigning/controlling|to reign, 町[まち, ちょう]:town|street|109.09 m||, 物語[ものがたり]:tale/story/legend, 終える[おえる]:to finish|to graduate, ちょうど:exactly/precisely|as if, ちょうど:supplies/furniture/fixtures, 頃合い[ころあい]:suitable time/good time|propriety
かつて白蛇が君臨したこの町の物語を終えるには
ちょうどいい頃合いだろう
We're starting our counterattack!
反撃[はんげき]:counterattack/counteroffensive/counterblow, 開始[かいし]:start/commencement/beginning
反撃開始だよん